# A AKRAM BASHA

D No: 5-123 Urbancolony, Kuppam, 517425, Andhra Pradesh a.akrambasha123@gmail.com | 8096105834 | DOB:15/10/2002

https://akrambasha123.github.io/portfolio/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/akram-basha-a-b45531250

# **Objective**

#### **Computer Science and Engineering Graduate**

A recent graduate from Kuppam Engineering College, With one year of experience as a Web Developer. I am passionate about technology and eager to start a career in a forward-thinking organization. I aim to utilize my skills in web development to contribute to the company's growth and stay updated with the latest industry trends.

# **Professional Experience**

#### DigitalHub Academy - (Web Developer Intern)

May 2023 - July 2023

- Worked on web development projects, helping with both front-end and back-end tasks.
- Learned from senior developers and contributed to creating and testing features.

#### **Digital Kuppam - (Full stack Developer)**

July 2023 - Present

- Developed and implemented front-end and back-end solutions for various web projects.
- Utilized technologies such as HTML, CSS, Laravel, SQL and PHP to enhance user experience and optimize website performance.

#### **Education**

Qualification		Institution	Year	percentage
BTech - 0	CSE	Kuppam Engineering College	2020-2024	80%
Intermediate -	MPC	IRM Junior College	2018-2020	93%
SSC		MFC Govt Boys High School	2017-2018	98%

## **Projects**

#### Titled as "G Star-Elevators"

Jan 25, 2024 - Present

- A service-based website designed to showcase company services and manage client quotations via an admin panel.
- **Link**: https://gstarelevators.com/
- Technologies: Web tools (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), Frameworks (Bootstrap-5, JQuery-3, AJAX, etc.), JSON, Laravel, SQL.

#### Titled as "CRM Workspace"

Oct 01, 2023 - Dec 20, 2023

- Developed a robust CRM website with features for lead tracking, communication logs, and task management to enhance client engagement and retention.
- **Link**: https://crmworkspace.in/
- Technologies: Web tools (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), Frameworks (Bootstrap-5, AJAX, Data Tables, etc.), JSON, PHP, SQL.

### **Internships**

- 12-Week Virtual Internship, Palo Alto Cybersecurity

  Gained hands-on experience in cybersecurity, focusing on real-world security challenges and solutions.
- 2-Month Web Development Internship, Data Lense Service Pvt Ltd
   Acquired practical skills in web development, contributing to various projects and learning industry standard practices.

### **Final Year Project College Project**

ightharpoonup Titled as "**Trend Trove**" (*Version -1 and Version -2*)

Feb 01, 2024

- An e-commerce platform designed with a focus on user-friendly interfaces and seamless shopping experiences. Managed both user and admin panels, and automated communication processes. Implemented features include shopping carts, checkouts, Wishlist's, and automated email notifications.
- **Technologies**: Web tools (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), Frameworks (Bootstrap-5, JQuery-3, AJAX, Data Tables, etc.), JSON, Laravel, SQL.

#### **Technical Skills**

Programming language : C, JAVA, PythonWeb development : HTML, CSS, PHP

> Tools : Postman, Jira, CI/CD, Linux

Frameworks : Bootstrap-5, JQuery-3, AJAX, Data Tables, Laravel

Databases : SQL, DBMSServers : Wamp, XAMPP

#### **Paper Presentations**

Design CNN Algorithm for Accident Identification

Presented at NCRICCT'22, Kuppam Engineering College.

Emotion Recognition for Students

Presented at the National Technical Symposium, Government College of Bargur.

#### **Certifications**

- NPTEL Certified in Software Project Management
- NPTEL Certified in Cloud Computing
- TCS ION Certified in Career Edge Young Professional (Soft Skills Course)
- Two-Month Internship (Data Lense Service)

#### **Skills**

- Superior time management
- Strong listening abilities
- Adaptability

### **Languages Known**

- English
- Hindi
- Telugu
- Urdu